<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ciprian Turcu&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>http://ciprianturcu.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ciprian Turcu&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 18:27:30 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ciprianturcu.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What have I been up to?</title>
      <link>http://ciprianturcu.com/post/what-have-I-been-up-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 18:27:30 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ciprianturcu.com/post/what-have-I-been-up-to/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;angular-2-4&#34;&gt;Angular 2, 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I feel I have been lately though. I have been studying Angular 2 for most of the time lately. Learning it&amp;rsquo;s ins and outs , doing the official tutorials and right now I&amp;rsquo;m doing a course about it on Udemy. Thing is, it&amp;rsquo;s been so much information. I think the guy that built the course must have done it in months. The course is 36 hours long and covers a lot of Angular 2 core inner workings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, angular 4 came officially out and now we all have to figure it out and what it brings new to the table. So that&amp;rsquo;s fun. Hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet gotten to exploring that. But I will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-plan&#34;&gt;The plan?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to get to know the basics: string interpolation, databinding, two way databinging, properties, directives, components, how and what goes where, how does the angular CLI work, what it can do for me, Routing, HTTP, dependency injection. The usual stuff. After that, I want to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make one project with angular 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn a html open source blog in an angular 2 one page app (like the paste app I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing in some other posts here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the angular 2 repository on github by fixing some issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding a better app to work on and do that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a rough plan so far. More to come, more will come and I will be updating stuff here as I have stuff ready.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile to Desktop incognito Paste</title>
      <link>http://ciprianturcu.com/post/mobile-to-desktop-incognito-paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 18:15:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ciprianturcu.com/post/mobile-to-desktop-incognito-paste/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There is no solution out there, for when I want to paste something from my mobile smart-phone to a computer that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to log into to have any sort of service at my disposal to do the sharing of text. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about when you want to share a link to a desktop pc from your phone, and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go to facebook on the desktop pc, log in, add your highly secure password and hope for the best, all just to paste a link of a cat video. or the winning lottery tickets numbers, or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-is-no-service-that-helps-you-do-that&#34;&gt;There is no service that helps you do that.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recentlty was trying to print something at a print house and in order to do that I had a pdf in my google drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the most obvious way was to send that PDF to a email and communicate with other people and ask them to print that for you. Right. Well, the other people where a bit busy, I did not want them to have my email address, because I&amp;rsquo;m selfish in that way, and, well, the problem was actually that they did not have stuff set up to receive an email , and print it for their customers. Yeah, they suck like that. Yes, My country lives in a cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically the google drive link was huge so I could not write every single character of it in time until it closed the printhouse. Even though it was morning. But there was an idea that popped in my head. What if&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m going to&amp;hellip;. YES!!! shorten that url, and write that character by character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That worked, and I did that for the next months (had something to do at the printhouse every month). Things tarted to get really boring and dumb really fast. There needs to be a better way. So &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched for sollutions online that can help me. Turns out, all of the results I found where apps, that you can install on your phone and you can sync your computer to. Awesome. Not what I was looking for. I need no login. at all. I&amp;rsquo;m going to a public print house. I just need a system that can help me receive a pasted text from my phone. That is all. This is 2017, come on technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-sollution&#34;&gt;The sollution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t see anything in the horizon so I&amp;rsquo;m going to build it myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on a app in Angular2 and GoLang that helps me solve my above problem. The result of this will be a MVP that will reside at &lt;a href=&#34;http://toolaxy.com/paste&#34;&gt;http://toolaxy.com/paste&lt;/a&gt; . Still working on it. Will make a post about it when it&amp;rsquo;s finished. Until then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my site</title>
      <link>http://ciprianturcu.com/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 17:22:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ciprianturcu.com/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is my new website where I will keep updates of my progress of everything I do, here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must warn you, I do change really fast, you&amp;rsquo;ll see my past examples. I change to evolve, to test, to figure out from my own experience and go to the next level ASAP. I change to get things done. I change to test. I change because , right now, I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-a-bit-of-backstory&#34;&gt;For a bit of backstory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quit my dayjob about 3 weeks ago and am working full time for myself. No projects for clients so far. And I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to have projects from clients. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to build my own product and or service. But there&amp;rsquo;s nothing of that either. Yet. I do have some Ideas. I quit because I wanted to do my own stuff, to work on my own dreams, and not somebody else&amp;rsquo;s. I can&amp;rsquo;t say I was&amp;rsquo;t inspired by some books I read. In a cliche-ish way, one that was Steve Job&amp;rsquo;s biography and one that is Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s biography. Combined, and after some processing time, I had a decision that I made a little over a year ago. Where I decided I was going to quit. But, because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any resources gathered, I was going to stay for 6 more months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up staying for 1 year. But here I am now, one year later. With no project, no idea and no clear path to go on. Scary, right? the money is going to run out. Eventually. I&amp;rsquo;d better get to work. NOW!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thing is, I don&amp;rsquo;t want that to be the motivator for my progress. I have a company now, named ToolAxy One. That&amp;rsquo;s formed from &amp;ldquo;tools&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;galaxy&amp;rdquo;. The name came out of the idea that I was going to make on it, a hand full of useful tools. One is there for 2 reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To try to make the name unique, to show that it is the first one, the only one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because just ToolAxy was taken and is too simple for today&amp;rsquo;s company names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s the story behind that name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was originally a WordPress developer. I worked with and on WordPress for about 10 years now. It was time for a change a while back. But I refused to see that, I wanted to contribute more, to try, to give more, to bring value, to WordPress. I wanted. So I searched for new, more exciting, more capable Software Development oportunities. I studied and tried Swift 3 for iOS 10. You know, the programming language for iphone, iPad, OSX, iWatch? right. The market there is overblown, the competition is fierce and there are limitations created by apple for it&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem. I did not want to make a &amp;ldquo;me too&amp;rdquo; type of idea and most ideas&amp;hellip; well.. there&amp;rsquo;s an app for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave some time to ReactJS. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. it&amp;rsquo;s great. Standalone, with nothing. It does it&amp;rsquo;s job well. But if you want to do 2 way data binding, you want to create routes, you want to create a full blown app quick. well, you will have to organize. There is no Quick. there&amp;rsquo;s just a lot of work, you need libraries like Redux that have a ton of components and dependencies for each and every feature. And if one component has an error or is incompatible because of it&amp;rsquo;s version to a modification/feature that is needed. The whole thing crashes and does not work. there needs to be a better organizing path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I learned and did a personal project in Angular 1.5.x but later, angular 2 came out of beta. It was weird, did not give it much thought. I am giving it thought now. and I am studying it, planning to make a new project on it. Won&amp;rsquo;t give details about that just yet, but I will as soon as I have something. All that I can say is that this project will need to be finished fast. And I will have a MVP as soon as possible (my target is by 1 April).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what I can say for now, is , I&amp;rsquo;m going all in Angular 2. I&amp;rsquo;m also going all in to another programming language, but that is for later. Thank you for reading thus far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always want more, it&amp;rsquo;s never enough, there&amp;rsquo;s so much information outh there that you can&amp;rsquo;t really settle. Unless you want to be a plain waste of air. Then you should settle. So many people have. Just Fuck, eat, shit and sleep. If that&amp;rsquo;s what your life purpose to be, fine. You have that right. I don&amp;rsquo;t. I want more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>